Believe in angels.
The Crow is a fantasy, action, thriller film directed by Alex Proyas.
Exactly one year after young rock guitarist Eric Draven and his fiancée are brutally killed by a ruthless gang
of criminals, Draven, watched over by a hypnotic crow, returns from the grave to exact revenge.
Eric, played by Brandon Lee.
Sarah, played by Rochelle Davis.
Albrecht, played by Ernie Hudson.
Top Dollar, played by Michael Wincott.
Myca, played by Bai Ling.
Shelly, played by Sofia Shinas.
The Crow is a 1994 American gothic supernatural superhero film
directed by Alex Proyas and written by David J.
Schow and John Shirley, based on the 1989 comic book series by James O'Barr.
It stars Brandon Lee in his final film role, as Eric Draven, a rock musician who is resurrected
from the dead to seek vengeance against the gang who murdered him and his fiancée.
Lee was fatally wounded by a prop gun during filming.
As he had finished most of his scenes, the film was completed through
script rewrites, a stunt double and digital effects.
After Lee's death, Paramount Pictures opted out of distribution
and the rights were acquired by Miramax Films.
The film is dedicated to Lee and his fiancée, Eliza Hutton.
The Crow premiered in Santa Monica on May 10, 1994, and was released in
the United States on May 13, 1994, by Dimension Films.
The film received positive reviews for its stylized noir
aesthetic, emotional resonance and Lee's performance.
It grossed $94 million on a $23 million budget and has gained a cult following.
The success led to three sequels, a television series, and a 2024 reboot,
all of which failed to replicate the first movie's success.
The film explores themes of martial arts,
superhero, supernatural, halloween, crow.
The tone is dark and intense.